DHR&Hakugetsu Sub
翻譯：因果律 モビイ·ディック 大湿 時間軸：水姬 後期：水姬 壓制：沙夏 KoU
Ever since that day,
あの日以来
I've been thinking,
is this really for the best?
ホントに
これで良かったのかと思う
貴様に礼弥を預けよう
I leave Rea to you.
Now that Rea's icky father
has entrusted her to me,
あの　きんもいオヤジから
礼弥を預かることになった俺は
I'm more keenly aware
of the weight of my responsibility
礼弥を自由にしてやれた
嬉しさよりも
than I am of the happiness
I feel over Rea being set free.
どっちかっつーと
責任の重さを実感している
Nemurenai yoru ni kiita monogatari ga
What if the story I heard that sleepless night
esoragoto da to shitara
was all just an impossible dream?
Eien wo shiru yori kairaku wo motomete
What if I pursue pleasure, and lament the moment
ima wo kuyande shimau no wa
instead of learning about the eternities
kokoro no fukaku ni sumitsuita kage kara
so that I can escape from the shadows
nigeru tame da to shitara
that dwell deep within my heart?
Sore demo atashi wa atashi wa ai shite irareru nara
But even so, as long as I, as long as I can still keep loving
Hanbun ni wareta taiyou ga asa wo tsurete kite
The sun split in half brings with it the morning
yami ni nareta shinkei wo jiwari shigeki suru
gradually stimulating my nerves, so used to the darkness
Okiwasureta ano ai wa aete sono mama de
I'll dare to leave the love that I'd misplaced as it is
Shinario no kieta monogatari wa
A story whose plot has been erased,
jiyuu ni jiyuu ni kaji wo totte
freely, freely, takes the helm,
motto takaku e maiagatte
soaring ever higher
No!!
ノ～ッ！　味噌汁に
ナスを入れるとは何事かッ
What's the big idea,
putting eggplant in the miso soup?!
"At That Moment... I..."
じーじ　それはピーマンだが
Gramps, those are green peppers.
Huh?
They are?
そうか
萌路
Mero...
What is it?
何か？
Rea's food seems to be awfully unique.
礼弥ちゃんの食事が
えらく独特のようだが
I've cooked for Lady Rea
according to her preference.
礼弥殿の好みに合わせて
料理したのです
あじさいの葉の　おひたし
Boiled hydrangea leaves...
Stir-fried hydrangea leaves...
あじさいの葉の炒め物
Hydrangea leaf broth...
あじさいの葉の煮汁
Are they any good?
美味しいのか？
やれるだけのことは
やったのだが
I've done everything that
I can, but I do feel limited.
限界は感じている
Rea did say she was
a vegetarian, right?
礼弥はベジタリアンだって
言っただろ
あじさいがベジタブルかね？
ごめんなさい
Are hydrangeas vegetables?
I'm sorry. I really should
eat by myself, shouldn't I?
私　やっぱり一人で食事した方が
いいですね
Oh, no, I didn't mean it like that.
あッ　いや
そういう意味じゃないんだよ
Daddy, please,
don't poke your nose in so much.
父ちゃん　あんまり
ツッコまないでやってくれよ
すまん　見慣れない料理に
ちょっと驚いただけなんだ
Sorry, I'm just a little surprised
by such unfamiliar cuisine.
No, please, don't let it bother you.
いえ　気になさらないでください
清！
Kiyo...
うわッ　清～ッ！
Kiyo!
ばーぶ
Grandpa sometimes gets
like this, so if he does, do that.
じいちゃん　たまに　こんなだから
何かあったら　こうして
R-Right.
あッ　はい
Sorry about all of this, Rea.
色々すまんな　礼弥ちゃん
Not at all.
いえ
I feel like, it's my duty.
ギリだよなあ　と思う
Everyone besides Grandpa
may think it's weird,
じいちゃん以外　みんな
おかしいと思ってんだろうけど
but they're all too nice
to say anything about it.
黙っててくれるのは
みんな優しいからだ
But then, obviously,
that's because they're family.
つうか　はっきり家族だからだ
Looking after a person
really is a hard thing to do.
ひと一人　面倒見るって
大変なことなんだな
Particularly so for a zombie.
ましてや　ゾンビとなると
ばーぶ
うんッ？
なあ
あッ
Say...
はい
Yes?
What can I say? I wish
I could take you to more places.
なんつうか
もっと　いろんなとこに
連れてってあげたいんだけどさ
Right.
はい
I'm sorry that this is all I can do for you.
ごめんな　こんなことぐらいしか
できなくて
I wouldn't say that.
I'm enjoying myself.
そんなことないですよ　楽しいです
When I was at home,
I couldn't do things like this.
家にいた頃は　こんなこと
できなかったんですから
Really?
ホントか？
Yes.
はい
あッ…　降谷君
Furuya...
There's a fireworks show tomorrow night.
明日　花火大会があるんですね
Yeah, they do that every year.
I've never gone to it, though.
ああ　毎年やってんなあ
俺　行ったことないけど
How nice.
いいなあ
I've always watched it from my room,
私　いつも自分の部屋から
眺めていたので
and I always wanted to see it from below.
一度　下から見てみたいと
思っていたんです
You wanna go?
行くか
えッ　いいんですか？
Huh? Can we?
A fireworks show will be
at night, so sure, I'll take you.
花火大会なら夜だし
連れてってやるよ
ホントに？
Really?!
じゃあ私
明日までに体が腐らないように
Well, I'll do everything
I possibly can to make sure
that my body doesn't
decay before tomorrow.
最大限の努力をしておきます
You're not going to decay that quickly.
そんな急に腐るかよ
What am I going to do with you,
しょうがねえなあ
花火くらいでこんなに喜ぶなんて
getting this worked up about fireworks?
What are you, a child?
子供かよ
子供ですッ　問題ありますか？
Yes, I am! Is there a problem with that?
Don't go turning on me!
開き直んなよ
礼弥の体を維持する方法
Although I've investigated many
methods of sustaining Rea's body,
エンバーミングや防腐剤
such as embalming, or using preservatives,
色々調べてみても
有効な手立ては　みつからない
I haven't been able to
find any effective measures.
And that's no surprise.
そりゃそうだ　ゾンビの腐敗を
食い止める方法なんて
After all, who is going to
come up with any hypotheses
on how to keep zombies from decaying?
誰も前提として考えないもんな
Huh? Aren't you going upstairs?
えッ　上に行かないんですか？
ああ　ちょっとな
Yeah, in a bit.
頼りにできるのは
じいちゃんだけなのだが
The only one I can turn to is Grandpa, but...
どうすりゃ　礼弥と礼弥の生活を
守ってあげられるのだろう？
How am I supposed to
protect Rea, and her lifestyle?
おッ？
にー　何をしておる？
Brother, what are you doing?
ああ　ちょっとな
Oh, not much...
By the way, is Lady Rea
to be going to school?
ところで　礼弥殿は
学校に行ったりはされないのか？
School? That may be pushing things a bit.
学校？　それはちょっと
無理っつうか
What is it now?
どうして　また？
健康上の理由ってヤツでさ
There are certain health reasons.
There aren't any problems that I could see.
見たところ
問題なさそうだが
No, not that you could see.
見たところはな
But on the inside,
things are all sorts of messed up.
でも中身が　色々大変でさ
When I went to school
in the morning she said to me...
朝　学校に行くとき言われたのだ
"School, huh? I'm so jealous."
「学校か　うらやましいな」と
Oh...
そう
病気なら
If she's ill, she could come home early,
早退とか　１日おきに登校するとか
色々　手はあろうに
or go every other day;
there are all sorts of ways she could go.
I can't really let her do that.
そういうわけにも　いかねえんだよ
では礼弥殿は　ずっと
うちにいることになるわけか
Then, Lady Rea must stay
at home from now on, is that it?
She's right. What do I do?
そう　どうすんだ？
今の暮らしが　礼弥にとって
普通の生活って言えるのか？
Can you call living like
this a normal life for Rea?
Can you call that being a normal girl?
普通の女の子だって
言えるのか？
Is her life too much for me to bear?
あいつの人生
俺には重すぎないか？
As though to echo my own mood,
そんな俺の気分を
反映したように
the fireworks show was called off, due to rain.
花火大会は
雨で　つぶれてしまった
Cancelled, huh?
中止か…
I guess there's nothing we can do, huh?
仕方ないですよね
何か　ごめんな
Yeah, sorry about that.
Furuya, why are you apologizing?
何で　降谷君が謝るんですか？
何となく
I just am.
I don't understand.
意味分かりません
Supposing...
もし
ばーぶ
Supposing I'm not gone,
and am still around,
もし私が　いなくなってなかったら
please take me next year.
来年　連れてってください
Promise me?
約束ですよ
The fireworks show
being called off also means
花火大会が
つぶれたってことは
that we missed a chance to mingle
with a bevy of beauties in yukatas.
浴衣美人の群れと
出会い損ねたってことだよな？
それって　俺のような
純情な高校生にとっては
For a red-blooded high-schooler
like me, that's a huge part of life
we're missing out on, if you ask me.
人生の重大な損失だと思うけど
どうよ？
What about you?
Yasutaka, you don't care who they
are, as long as they're female, huh?
ヤスタカ君は　女の人なら
誰でもいいんだもんね
て　お前なッ
そういうこと言ってんじゃねえ
Now listen, you!
That's not what I'm saying at all!
これは　いわゆる　その…　何だ？
It's more like, say, you know...
Furuya, you, too?
降谷よ　お前もか
何が？
What?
You're picturing the Sanka girls
散女の女子を　浴衣姿に
脳内変換してるんだよな？
wearing yukatas in your head, too, huh?
No I'm not, you perv.
ちげーよ　変態
Chihiro!
千紘～
おっはよう
ああ　わんこ
Good morning!
Yeah, Wanko.
What are you spacing off about?
何　ボケッとしてんの？
何でもねえよ
Nothing at all.
You were thinking about
that young lady again, weren't you?
また　あのお嬢様のこと
考えてたんじゃないの？
I was not.
そんなんじゃねえって
Come on!
こらッ　お姉さんに話してみろって
Tell your big sister all about it!
You're hurting me!
- And what was that about
being your fiancé before?!
- Must be nice.
- And what was that about
being your fiancé before?!
いいなあ
ホントに誰でもいいんだね
- You really will go for anyone, huh?
- And what was that about
being your fiancé before?!
- You really will go for anyone, huh?
- Cousin's prerogative!
- I won't deny it.
- Gah! Sorry! I'm sorry!
否定はしな～い
The fireworks show, huh?
花火大会ね
あいつ　楽しみにしてたからさ
She was really looking forward to it.
I was looking forward to it, too.
I was all ready to go with you.
私も楽しみにしてたよ
千紘と行く気満々でさ
そうかよ
Oh, yeah?
じゃあさ
ちっちゃい花火大会やろっか？
Well then, how about if we
throw our own small fireworks show?
Lady Rea...
礼弥殿
礼弥殿に手伝っていただいては
Lady Rea, it would be unpardonable
to Brother to have you help me.
にーに　申し訳が立ちませぬ
Something like this is no big deal.
これくらい平気ですよ
いや　しかし
Yes, but still...
I said it's no big deal.
平気ですってば
What exactly just happened?
これはいったい　どういう…
ごめんね　萌路ちゃん
Sorry about that, Mero.
I'm home.
ただいま
降谷君　おかえりなさい
Furuya, welcome home.
Brother, you're home early.
にー　早かったですな
What are you doing,
cleaning out in broad daylight?
何やってんだよ
真っ昼間に掃除なんて
Not to mention that broom...
しかも　そのほうき
えッ　大丈夫ですよ
I-It's all right. It's cloudy,
and besides, you worry too much.
曇りだし　降谷君　心配しすぎです
Oh, really?
ホントかよ
本当です
Yes, really.
後で　よく休んどけよ
はい
Make sure to get plenty of rest later.
Right.
Also, I should mention,
we're having our own fireworks show.
そう言っといて何だけど
俺達だけで花火大会やろうぜ
A fireworks show?
花火大会？
Mm-hmm.
うん　今夜ここでさ
Tonight, right here. We can at
least shoot some bottle rockets.
ロケット花火くらいなら
打ち上げられるぜ
We haven't done fireworks in a long time.
花火など　久しくやっておらなんだ
楽しそうですね
It sounds like fun.
決まりだな
That settles it.
Wanko said she would
lend you a yukata, so wear that.
わんこが浴衣貸してくれるから
着てみろよ　着付けもしてくれる
She said she'd even help dress you up.
It won't feel like the real thing,
but let's make the most of it.
気分だけどさ　それらしくしようぜ
わんこさん　来られるんですか？
Miss Wanko is coming, too?
They'll be her fireworks.
I'll go get my yukata, too.
花火も　あいつの
俺も浴衣出しとくわ
Okay, when Wanko gets
here, let her know, okay?
じゃ　わんこが来たら
そういうことで
私も夕飯の支度がありますゆえ
I have to get supper ready, too, so...
うん　ここは片付けておくから
Mm-hmm. I'll clean up out here.
If you please. Okay then...
頼みましたぞ　では
わんこさん　か
Miss Wanko, huh...?
Hello!
こんにちはー！
Hi, Ranko. Come on in.
やあ蘭子ちゃん　いらっしゃい
I hear you're putting on fireworks.
花火やるんだって？
はい
Yes! We hated that they got cancelled,
中止が悔しかったから
せめて私達だけでも　と思って
so we thought we could at least do our own.
Yo, Wanko.
よう　わんこ
あッ
Look at you! You got it on just fine, huh?
何だ　うまく着れてんじゃん
うん　萌路に着つけてもらったんだ
Mm-hmm. I had Mero help me dress.
Well, I'm used to putting
them on all the time, after all.
何　普段から
着慣れておりますのでな
So, where's Rea?
で　礼弥ちゃんは？
上にいるよ
She's upstairs. Rea!
礼弥～！
Is it okay for me to be tying the belt up?
帯とか締めても平気かな？
あッ　全然平気です
Ah, no problem at all.
In fact, I'd like you
to wrap it nice and tight.
むしろ　いっそう強く
締めてもらいたいくらいです
Okay.
そう
Miss Wanko, you're pretty
close to Furuya, aren't you?
わんこさんは
降谷君と仲がいいんですよね
I sure am. We've been
friends since childhood, after all.
いいよ　幼なじみだからね
He's always been a bit of an oddball.
あいつ　昔から変わり者だったから
最初はムカついてたんだけど
At first, he annoyed me,
but he has a lot of other good points.
いいとこも　いっぱいあるんだよね
That's why he's dear to me.
だから大事にしてる
そうですか
I see.
Ordinarily, he wouldn't
be interested in fireworks,
あいつ　普段だったら
花火なんか興味ないはずなのに
but when I suggested
we do this, he got on board.
私が「やろう」って言ったら
のっちゃってさ
He's so simple. He figures
that this will please you, Rea.
単純なの
礼弥ちゃんが喜ぶと思ったんだよ
I'm not sure if he's a good guy,
or a not-so-good guy,
いいヤツなんだか
やなヤツなんだか分かんないけど
but ultimately, he is a good guy.
結局　いいヤツなの
I sort of understand what you mean.
私も　それ　ちょっと分かります
Okay!
はい　終わったよ
All done. Face this way.
こっち向いてみて
はい
Okay.
It just seems so out of place, you know?
全然違和感ないよね
えッ？
To think that the girl standing
before my eyes is a zombie...
私の目の前にいる人が
ゾンビだなんて
How can I be sure you're not really alive?
ホントは
死んでないんじゃないの？
No, I'm really not.
I don't have a pulse, or anything.
そんなことないですよ
脈だって　ありませんし
Except for the wound to your stomach,
you're normal, aren't you?
おなかの傷以外は普通じゃない？
I don't know how long
I can remain in this condition.
いつまで　この状態でいられるかも
分かりません
I don't have all that much time.
そんなに時間はないんです
My body is starting to spoil.
体も　傷んできてますし
えッ　わ…　わんこさん？
M-Miss Wanko?
Mm-mm, smells perfectly fine to me.
うん　全然平気じゃない
Hydrangeas, were they?
They seem to be working, aren't they?
あじさいだっけ　あれが
ちゃんと効いてんじゃない？
And Chihiro will be
coming up with something, too.
これからも
千紘が何とかしてくれるって
Yes, you're right.
ええ　そうですね
You'll be here for good, I tell you.
ずっと　ここにいられるって
いえ　別に　ずっといるつもりは…
Huh? Oh, no,
I don't intend to stay here long...
Then, you're going somewhere else?
じゃあ　別のとこに行くの？
Er, that much is still...
I don't know, I guess.
いや　まだ　その…
分かんないっていうか
You see, if I stay too long,
it will put everyone out, so...
その…　ずっとだと
色々　迷惑だろうし
I see. He would probably
miss you, you know.
そっか　あいつ寂しがるだろうね
D-Do you think so?
そ　そうでしょうか？
Um, Miss Wanko, are you... and Furuya...
あの　わんこさんは　その…
降谷君のことが…
I love him. How about you?
好きだよ　あなたは？
Huh? Me? I, um...
it's nothing too remarkable...
えッ？　私は　その…
そんな大それたことは
Then it's okay if I monopolize
Chihiro all to myself.
じゃあ　いいんだ？
私が千紘を独り占めしちゃっても
Well...
Well, I think... that would be... fine...
それは　それでいいと…
Rea, listen, are you, by any chance,
just being polite with me?
礼弥ちゃんさ　ひょっとして
私に気を使ってる？
Huh? W-W-What do you mean?
えッ　な　何のことですか？
Oh, geez, you know what,
Rea, you're an open book.
もう　なんつうか
礼弥ちゃん　バレバレ
What I mean is, Rea, you and
I have become rivals, haven't we?
要するにさ　私と礼弥ちゃんは
ライバルってことだよね
Uh... well...
あッ　えと…
But Miss Wanko, I'm not
nearly as close to Chihiro as you are.
でも　私は　わんこさんほど
降谷君とは近しい仲ではないし
A-And when Furuya looks at me,
he just admires me as a zombie.
降谷君が私を見る目だって
ゾンビだから愛でているだけだし
For crying out loud!
まったくもう　何遠慮してんのよッ
What are you holding back for?!
It's do-or-die time, right?
If you don't have any time,
なおさらでしょ
時間がないんだったらさ
then you've got to live like it's
now or never, or regret it forever!
なおさら　後悔しないように
生きなきゃ　オンナノコなら
If you wanna be a girl!
Miss... Wanko...
わんこ　さん…
I'm already dead, though.
私　もう死んでますけど
I'm not all that good
when it comes to mushy stuff.
私さ　ドロドロしたの
得意じゃないんだ
And even if you are in love with Chihiro,
礼弥ちゃんが
千紘のこと好きだとしても
I am who I am, and you are who you are.
私は私　あなたはあなただから
I'm not going to bow out, that's all.
ただ　私は負けないってだけ
So, Rea, you hang in there, yourself, too.
だから　礼弥ちゃんは礼弥ちゃんで
頑張って
Right.
はい
Having fun?
楽しいか？
楽しいですよ
Yes, I am.
Sorry we couldn't do anything bigger than this.
ごめんな　こんな程度のことしか
できなくてさ
Furuya, you sure apologize a lot, huh?
降谷君　やたらと謝りますよね
Well, I mean...
だって　そりゃ…
You don't have anything to worry about.
気にすることないですよ
I'm content with just
having something here at all.
こちらに置いていただいて
それだけで私は満足なんです
You're not bored by it?
退屈じゃないか？
いいえ
Nope.
Are you dissatisfied with anything?
何か不満はないのかよ？
ないです
No, nothing.
It's refreshing, and stimulating,
ここで　降谷君達と
生活できることが新鮮だし
being able to live together with you guys.
刺激的なんです
Right now, I think these smaller
fireworks are much nicer
今は　大きな花火よりも
小さな花火の方が
than any big fireworks.
素敵だと思います
I'm home.
ただいま
W-Welcome home.
お　おかえりなさいませ
What is the matter, Mistress?
どうなさったのですか？
お嬢様
I'm going back to school.
学校に戻ります
I came to get the things I would
need for that. That's okay, right?
そのための荷物を取りに来ました
かまいませんよね？
Y-Yes...
は　はい
Tell the madam.
奥様に
As you wish.
かしこまりました
Mother...
お母様
I hear you're going back to school.
学校に戻るんですって？
Yes. That's what I've decided.
はい　そう決めました
You've got your nerve, planning
to go back to Dan'ichiro's school.
どの面下げて　通うつもり？
団一郎さんの学校に
Do you intend to expel me from the school?
退学になさる　おつもりですか？
いいえ
No, Dan'ichiro told me not to do anything.
団一郎さんからは何もするなって
言われてるから　何もしないわ
So I won't. Do as you wish.
好きにしたら
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございます
However, I really won't do anything.
ただし　ホントに何もしないわよ
No worrying, no consideration,
no helping hands.
心配も　気遣いも　手助けも
I am ready for that.
覚悟してます
Well, if you've finished your
business, head on out of here.
じゃ　用事がすんだら
とっとと出てって
If you'll excuse me...
失礼します
You okay?
平気か？
あッ　はい
Y-Yes.
Thank you, Furuya. About school, I mean.
ありがとう　降谷君　学校のこと
Well, you want to go, right?
だって　行きたいんだろ？
Yes. Are you sure it's all right?
はい　ホントにいいんですか？
It's fine. Not much I can do about it.
いいよ　それくらい仕方ないって
I'm so happy.
嬉しいです
After all, if I don't go to school,
だって　学校通わないと
I don't think I can call myself
a normal girl, and I miss it a little.
普通の女の子って言えないな
って思って
ちょっと寂しかったんです
You really were dissatisfied, weren't you?
お前　不満あんじゃねえか
Was it dissatisfaction...?
I guess it was. I'm sorry.
不満っていうか…
そうですね　ごめんなさい
Just promise me that you'll be careful, okay?
ただし　約束してくれよ
気をつける　って
Right.
はい
Keep your efforts to preserve
your body combined with mine, okay?
お前の体を維持る努力
俺と一緒にしてくれよ
All right.
分かりました
I, uh...
俺さ
はい
Yes?
Can I be honest with you?
正直な話　していいか？
Please.
どうぞ
I'd like to keep you this way
for as long as I possibly can.
俺は　お前に　できるだけ長く
このままでいてほしいと思う
Can I be honest with you, too?
私も正直に話していいですか？
Yeah.
I don't want to leave behind any regrets.
私　後悔したくないんです
If I don't know when I might be gone,
いつ　いなくなるか分からないなら
then I have to do as much as I can.
やれるだけのことは
やっておかないと
That's what it is to be a girl!
それが　オンナノコですから
No use arguing, huh?
しょうがねえな
Nope, no use in arguing.
しょうがないですね
She's right.
そうだ　そうなんだ
She is right.
What makes me happy brings Rea down,
俺の幸せは　礼弥の不幸で
礼弥の幸せは　俺の不幸なんだ
and what makes Rea happy brings me down.
I get it. I get it, but still...
分かってる　分かってるけど
でも
If you're going to go to school, then you know,
学校行くんなら　やっぱさ
we should fix up that
coat so you can put dry ice in it.
あのコートに　ドライアイス
仕込めるようにした方がいいよな
But you'll only be wearing
the coat on the way there and back.
でも　コート着るの
行き帰りだけだもんな
What's more, you can't
wear it in the summertime.
それに夏場は着れないし
つうか　夏場にコートでも
変じゃないか
For that matter, any coat
would be weird in summertime.
What do you think?
お前　どう思う？
But at that moment...
でも　あの瞬間
I...
俺は
At that moment, I...
あの瞬間　俺は
...got the feeling that Rea and I
礼弥と　幸福と不幸を
分け合った気がしたんだ
shared our happiness and sadness.
At that moment...
あの瞬間
Hitotsu dake kanau no nara
If I had just one wish
kimi no te no naka yureru chiisa na hana de itai
I would want to be a small flower, trembling in your hands
Hajimete miru mabushii kono sekai ga
Even if I become separated from you,
kimi to moshi hagureta to shite mo kitto
in this bright world I'm seeing for the first time,
mitsukedashite
I'm sure I'll find you
Mezametara soba ni iru yo
When I wake up, I'll stay beside you
ashita mo
tomorrow as well
Preview
Next time...
Sankarea, episode 13:
"I, Too, Am... A Zombie..."
Everybody watch mero!
- You did it!
- Way to go!
"I, Too, Am... A Zombie..."
Oh, well, I couldn't have
made it this far all by myself.
I am overwhelmed with gratitude.
I thank you. I really do thank you.